[jaunty ukulele music]
[欢快的尤克里里音乐]
♪ ♪
- Why, you...
- 为什么，你...
- What I do?
- 我做什么？
- Why, you...
- 为什么，你...
- What I do?
- 我做什么？
- Why, you...
- 为什么，你...
- What I do?
- 我做什么？
- [laughing hysterically]
- [歇斯底里地大笑]
- Wow!
- 哇！
It's "The Sir Urchin
这就是《顽童先生》
and Snail Fail Show"!
和蜗牛失败秀”！
- It's cartoon time, SpongeBob!
- 海绵宝宝，卡通时间到了！
SpongeBob?
海绵宝宝？
[ponderous orchestral music]
[沉闷的管弦乐]
SpongeBob?
海绵宝宝？
♪ ♪
SpongeRobert?
海绵罗伯特？
- Oh!
- 哦！
It's cartoon time!
卡通时间到了！
I'll get our "Sir Urchin" hats.
我去拿我们的“顽童爵士”帽子。
Whoa.
哇哦。
- Not so fast, SpongeBob.
- 别那么快，海绵宝宝。
What's in the secret room?
密室里有什么？
- It's not a secret room,
Patrick.
- 这不是一个秘密房间，
帕特里克.
It's my library.
这是我的图书馆。
- W-what's that word mean?
- 这、这个词是什么意思？
- A library is a... playground
for your mind.
- 图书馆是...游乐场
为了你的心意。
- [vacant drone]
- [空置无人机]
[laughter]
[笑声]
Hm...
嗯...
[laughs]
[笑]
Let's do it!
It's library time!
我们开始做吧！
图书馆时间到了！
- Ow!
Ow!
- 噢！
噢！
- What I do?
- 我做什么？
[ukulele music]
[尤克里里音乐]
- [enthusiastic grunting]
- [热情的咕哝声]
[yells]
[喊叫]
- [meows]
- [喵]
[hisses]
[嘶嘶声]
- Oh, tender, naive Patrick,
-哦，温柔、天真的帕特里克，
it's not that kind
of playground.
不是那样的
的游乐场。
It's a place to read books!
See?
这是一个看书的地方！
看？
- I love books!
- 我喜欢书！
[laughing] Book!
[笑] 书！
Book!
书！
- Gary, I don't think
Patrick knows
- 加里，我不认为
帕特里克知道
how to use a book properly.
如何正确使用一本书。
Ow!
噢！
[ukulele music]
[尤克里里音乐]
Behold the books, Patrick.
看书吧，帕特里克。
Each one has a story to tell.
每个人都有一个故事要讲。
- Whoa.
- Look out!
- 哇哦。
- 小心！
Those books are cliffhangers,
那些书都是扣人心弦的，
stories for the adventurous.
适合冒险家的故事。
- [pained grunt]
- [痛苦的咕哝声]
[nervous yelling]
[紧张的叫喊]
I'll save you!
我来救你！
Whoa!
哇！
[dramatic orchestral music]
[戏剧管弦乐]
- There are logbooks,
- 有日志，
unabridged books,
未删节的书籍，
and books with bridges.
和有桥梁的书。
- Whoa!
- 哇！
[laughs]
[笑]
- Listen to the soothing sounds
- 聆听舒缓的声音
of the audiobooks.
有声读物。
[seagulls crying]
[海鸥的哭泣]
I can hear the ocean.
我能听到大海的声音。
[toilet flushing]
[冲厕所]
Me too!
我也是！
[laughter]
[笑声]
- Cookbooks,
for the culinarily curious.
- 食谱，
对于对烹饪感兴趣的人。
- [vacant grunting]
- [空洞的咕哝声]
I like the pictures.
我喜欢这些照片。
- Ah, but the pictures
are a mere snack!
- 啊，但是照片
只是零食！
It's the words in the book
that really feed your brain.
这是书上的话
这确实可以满足您的大脑需求。
Let's start you off
with an old book.
让我们开始吧
与一本旧书。
[light orchestral music]
[轻快的管弦乐]
[eerie music]
[诡异的音乐]
[sniffs]
Ah, musty old books smell.
[嗅嗅]
啊，旧书发霉的味道。
Now read the words, Patrick.
现在读一下这句话，帕特里克。
- Oh, read the--
- 哦，读一下——
oh, uh...
哦，呃...
"Once...
“一次...
Upon a..."
经一...”
"Once upon a"...
“从前”...
Once upon a what?
从前什么？
- To continue the story,
- 为了继续这个故事，
you have to turn the page.
你必须翻页。
- Oh.
- 哦。
"Time."
“时间。”
"Once upon a time"!
“曾几何时”！
[laughs]
[笑]
That's the most amazing trick
I've ever seen!
这才是最神奇的绝招
我见过！
I want to stare
at more words!
我想凝视
更多的话！
- Then feast your eyes!
-那就大饱眼福吧！
[ethereal music]
[空灵的音乐]
♪ ♪
Once upon a time...
曾几何时...
- [quavering]
- [颤抖]
Once a--
有一次——
You're too slow!
你太慢了！
[muttering]
[嘀咕]
- He likes it!
Hey, Patrick!
- 他喜欢！
嘿，帕特里克！
- [muttering]
- [嘀咕]
♪ ♪
- [sniffing]
- [嗅嗅]
[gasps]
[喘气]
♪ ♪
[industrious grunting]
[勤奋的咕哝]
♪ ♪
[dramatic orchestral music]
[戏剧管弦乐]
♪ ♪
- Ooh, Patrick, your head
is absorbing
- 哦，帕特里克，你的头
很吸引人
all the book knowledge,
书本上的所有知识，
just like a sponge!
就像海绵一样！
[laughs]
[笑]
♪ ♪
[laughs]
Go, Patrick!
[笑]
去吧，帕特里克！
Get those words!
明白这些话！
Get them good!
让他们好起来！
♪ ♪
- Stop reading words!
- 别再读文字了！
♪ ♪
- Wow, what a bookworm!
- 哇，真是个书呆子！
Whoa.
哇哦。
- Yes, SpongeBob?
- 是的，海绵宝宝？
- Uh, Patrick, I think
- 呃，帕特里克，我想
that's enough knowledge
for one day.
这些知识就足够了
一天。
Looks like you're full.
看来你已经吃饱了
- Nonsense, dear boy.
- 废话，亲爱的孩子。
One can never accumulate
too much information.
一个人永远无法积累
太多的信息。
[genteelly] Ahem.
[礼貌地]咳咳。
- Well, we're fresh
out of books.
- 嗯，我们很新鲜
没有书了。
Come on, I'll buy you
an ice cream.
来吧，我买给你
一个冰淇淋。
- Ah, I must confess to feeling
- 啊，我必须承认这种感觉
more than slightly peckish.
不仅仅是有点饿。
- Patrick, I'm so proud of you!
- 帕特里克，我为你感到骄傲！
Ooh, you're a big brain now!
呵呵，你现在脑子真大啊！
- Ooh!
- 哦！
Oh, a skosh too big, it seems,
eh, wha'?
哦，看起来太大了，
呃，什么？
- "Eh, wha'" what?
- [laughs]
- “呃，什么”什么？
- [笑]
Oh, no matter,
my plebeian friend.
哦，没关系，
我的平民朋友。
I shall simply
exit posthaste,
我将简单地
匆忙退出，
posterior-first.
后先。
Oof!
钱币！
- I got it.
- Careful.
- 我得到了它。
- 小心。
- Little bit...
Wow.
- 一点点...
哇。
You really got your melon
jammed in there, didn't you?
你真的得到了你的瓜
塞在那里，不是吗？
- Oh, true, SpongeBob.
- 噢，是的，海绵宝宝。
Eh, but we can easily
solve this problem
嗯，但是我们可以很容易地
解决这个问题
on a quantum physics level.
Take this down.
在量子物理层面上。
把这个拿下来。
If we reduce
my subatomic particles
如果我们减少
我的亚原子粒子
by way
of orbital electromagnetism,
顺便
轨道电磁学，
we'll create
a harmonic oscillation
我们将创造
简谐振动
within the molecules,
分子内，
resulting in
a wave-function collapse,
导致
波函数塌缩，
which will enable
my "melon,"
这将使
我的“瓜”
as you so drolly put it,
正如你滑稽地说的那样
to slip out.
溜出去。
- Okay, sure.
- 好吧，当然。
Let's give it a try.
让我们尝试一下。
[muttering]
[嘀咕]
[otherworldly music]
[超凡脱俗的音乐]
- [meows]
- [喵]
- Gary!
- 加里！
Speak to me.
跟我说话。
Oh...
哦...
- [meows]
- [喵]
- Oh, Gary, you're back.
- 哦，加里，你回来了。
I'd know that slime anywhere.
我会在任何地方都认识这种粘液。
[gasps]
Slime!
[喘气]
史莱姆！
That's it!
[laughs]
就是这样！
[笑]
Slime it up, Gar-bear.
把它粘起来，加熊。
- [laughs]
- [笑]
Abominable.
可恶。
- Yeah, that Gary grease
ought to do it.
- 是的，加里油脂
应该这样做。
Okay, Patrick,
pull yourself out.
好吧，帕特里克，
把自己拉出来。
[jaunty ukulele music]
[欢快的尤克里里音乐]
♪ ♪
[yells]
[喊叫]
Hey.
"Head Shrinking for Beginners."
嘿。
“初学者的头缩小”。
Hm...
嗯...
[energetic drum music]
【充满活力的鼓乐】
[screams]
[尖叫声]
[chicken clucks]
[鸡咯咯叫]
♪ ♪
[chanting, yelling]
[口号、喊叫]
♪ ♪
[chicken clucks]
[鸡咯咯叫]
[high-pitched] Oh, I give up!
[高调]哦，我放弃了！
I guess we'll have to live here
in the library forever, Gary.
我想我们得住在这里
永远在图书馆里，加里。
- [meows]
- [喵]
- [cries]
- [哭声]
- SpongeBob,
your typically moronic attempt
- 海绵宝宝，
你典型的愚蠢尝试
has given me the solution!
已经给了我解决方案！
Perhaps because
I had to smarten up
也许是因为
我必须变得聪明起来
to get stuck...
被困...
- You'll need to dumb down
to get free!
- 你需要冷静下来
获得自由！
- [laughs]
- [笑]
Who's sporting
the big brain now, hm?
谁在运动
现在脑子很大，嗯？
[laughs]
[笑]
- All right, Patrick.
- 好吧，帕特里克。
Let's get stupid!
让我们变得愚蠢吧！
Yeah!
是的！
[industrious ukulele music]
[勤奋的尤克里里音乐]
♪ ♪
Electronics.
电子产品。
♪ ♪
Whew.
呼。
I hope this works.
- Ah.
我希望这能起作用。
- 啊。
♪ ♪
- Why, you...
- 为什么，你...
- What I do?
- 我做什么？
- Why, you...
- 为什么，你...
- What I do?
- 我做什么？
- I'm sorry, dear boy,
- 对不起，亲爱的孩子，
but watching
this mindless drivel
但正在观看
这种无意识的胡言乱语
isn't affecting me
in the least.
没有影响我
至少。
[vacant moan]
[空洞的呻吟]
- We've got drool!
- 我们已经流口水了！
Patrick, it's working!
帕特里克，成功了！
- What I do?
- 我做什么？
- This is insulting
my intelligence.
- 这是侮辱性的
我的智力。
[laughing] And I adore it!
[笑]我喜欢它！
[lower,
more enthusiastic laughing]
[降低，
笑得更热情了]
[rumbling]
[隆隆声]
- What I do?
- 我做什么？
- Why, you...
- 为什么，你...
- What I do?
- 我做什么？
- [frightened noises]
- [惊恐的声音]
[crashing sounds]
[碰撞声]
- We did it, Patrick!
- 我们做到了，帕特里克！
The mindless drivel
is destroying your knowledge!
无脑的胡言乱语
正在摧毁你的知识！
- [laughs]
- [笑]
[vacant laughter]
[空洞的笑声]
[building orchestral music]
[构建管弦乐]
♪ ♪
Whoops.
Here, Patrick.
哎呀。
在这里，帕特里克。
You may need
this little fella.
您可能需要
这个小家伙。
- [vacant groan]
- [空洞的呻吟]
Huh?
啊？
Ah.
啊。
[ukulele music]
[尤克里里音乐]
♪ ♪
- Well, Patrick,
this is where we came in.
- 好吧，帕特里克，
这就是我们进来的地方。
Ready for some ice cream?
准备好吃冰淇淋了吗？
- Boy, am I ever!
- 男孩，我曾经吗！
Oof.
A book?
钱币。
一本书？
I love books!
我喜欢书！
[yells]
[喊叫]
A book!
[laughs]
一本书！
[笑]
- That's right, Patrick.
- 没错，帕特里克。
Play nice
with the pretty squares.
玩得好
和漂亮的方块。
Gary, this is really
one for the books, eh?
加里，这真的是
一本用于书籍，是吗？
[laughs]
- [meows dully]
[笑]
- [闷闷不乐地喵喵叫]
- [laughs]
- [笑]
♪ ♪